<dashboard>
  <label>Documentation</label>
  <row><panel>
  <html>
    <h2>makealerts</h2>
    <a name="makealerts"></a>
    <div class="row">
    <div class="span12">
      <p><code>makealerts</code> creates alerts from piped events. Syntax:</p>
      <pre>makealerts time=<em>fieldname</em> entity=<em>fieldname</em> type=<em>string</em> severity=<em>fieldname</em> idfield=<em>fieldname</em>
    combine=<em>"comma separated fieldnames"</em> combine_window=<em>duration_spec</em></pre>
      <p>This will insert alerts as records in the <em>alerts</em> kv store. All non-internal fields are saved. If an alert with same event time and the same field values already exists, then it will not be inserted.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>time is optional and defaults to the _time field</li>
        <li>entity is optional and defaults to the entity field</li>
        <li>type is a required string</li>
        <li>severity is an optional field name</li>
        <li>idfield is an optional field that will received the auto generated key from the alert kv insert operation</li>
        <li>combine and combine_window are optional fields to prevent multiple
        alerts by combining subsequent alerts with identical values for some
        fields within a time window:
            <ul>
                <li>combine is a list of comma separated field names enclosed in double quotes</li>
                <li>combine_window is a string to indicate a number of hours or
                days with the following format number[d|h] such as 1d or
                12h</li>
            </ul>
        </li>
        <li>interactive=t option is required to use makealerts from an interactive search; its purpose is to prevent the
        accidental creation of alerts when an analyst re-runs a saved search that is using the makealerts command - either the
        analyst needs to remove makealerts altogether, or he or she needs to adds interactive=t option</li>
        <li>preview=t option is used to preview if an alert would be created or not without actually creating it; the outcome is stored
        in the preview field</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Examples in scheduled searches</p>
      <pre>... | makealerts time=_time entity=user type="My Type"
... | makealerts time=_time entity=user type="My Type" combine="host,user,clientip,destip" combine_window=24h</pre>
      <p>Examples  in interactiver searches</p>
      <pre>... | makealerts time=_time entity=user type="My Type" interactive=t
... | makealerts time=_time entity=user type="My Type" interactive=t preview=t</pre>
    </div>
    </div>

    <h2>Canned Queries</h2>
    <a name="canned_queries"></a>
    <div class="row">
    <div class="span12">
      <p>One canned query can be provided for each alert type. They are configured in the
      <a href="search?q=%7C%20inputlookup%20canned_queries" target="_blank"> canned_queries</a> lookup table. The link can have placeholders
      that are replaced with details from the alert using the <code>&lt;%- alert.data.field %&gt;</code> syntax. The intent is to let
      you link to a Splunk dashboard of your choice.</p>
    </div>
    </div>
  </html>
  </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>
